iab.com 2019-09-09

# Privacy Policy

**Effective Date: July 19, 2018**

This is our official Privacy Policy which forms part of your legal agreement with us UNDER OUR [TERMS OF USE](https://www.iab.com/terms-of-use/). Please read our Privacy Policy carefully to be sure you understand how we collect and use information and under what circumstances we share information.

**CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY**  
We reserve the right, in our sole discretion, to modify, add or delete provisions of this Privacy Policy at any time. We will post the effective date of any change at the top of this Privacy Policy. Your use of our Website, which includes the Member Portal, after the effective date of any such modification means you accept and agree to be bound by the Privacy Policy, as modified. We urge you to come back to this page and review this Privacy Policy regularly so that you remain aware of the terms and conditions that apply to you.

**COLLECTING PERSONAL INFORMATION**  
“Personal Information” may include information such as your name, postal address, email, and telephone number. You voluntarily provide this information to us, for example, when you register with our Website (e.g., to access the Member Portal) or make a request for information or services. We may use this information for purposes including responding to your requests as well as to provide you access to interactive features (i.e., conferences or webinars). See the section entitled “How We Use Information” for more detail. We do not sell or rent your Personal Information to others except as otherwise disclosed in this policy. If necessary, our Website may collect payment and payment instrument information from you for the purpose of billing you for products, services, or event tickets you purchase through our Website.

**COLLECTING NON-PERSONAL INFORMATION**  
We use “cookies,” which are small text files stored on your computer/device (and maintained by your browser), and often include a randomized unique identifier so that our Website can ‘recognize’ this cookie again. We primarily use cookies that are considered ‘mandatory’ or ‘technically necessary’ to provide our Website and its core functionality to you (e.g., cookies that store your log-in information or remember other settings, so you don’t have to re-enter them each time you return to our Website), and Google Analytics for audience measurement purposes (as described below). Please note that we do not use, or engage other operational service providers or entities to use on our behalf, retargeting cookies (e.g., cookies that track you on our Website and across other websites in order to serve you a targeted advertisement) or other cookies that may track your experience on our Website in order to build user profiles. Should our use of cookies change in the future, we will update this Privacy Policy and notify you appropriately before such use (including obtaining your consent, as applicable).

We also use Google Analytics to obtain high-level “audience measurement” data such as the referral web domain, type of operating system/browser used, date and time of visit, and other information relating to activities on our Website to understand its usage better, analyze trends, and optimize the Website experience. To help ensure such data within Google Analytics cannot be linked back to an identifiable user, the last octet of all IP Addresses collected have been anonymized, ‘Sharing With Google,’ ‘Remarketing and Advertising,’ and ‘Demographics and Interests’ features have been disabled, and retention of analytics has been set to 14 months. For more information on Google Analytics, including how to opt-out please click here: <https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245.>

We do not use cookies to retrieve information from your computer or device for purposes that are unrelated to our Website or your interaction with our Website. You may stop or restrict cookies on your computer or purge them from your browser by adjusting your web browser preferences and you should consult the operating instructions that apply to your browser for instructions should you wish to do so and in general to determine how best to configure your browser settings to meet your requirements. Note that if you “turn off,” purge, or disable cookies, although you may still use our Website, you may not be able to use all of the features, functions, or services available on our Website.

**HOW WE USE INFORMATION**  
We will use information we collect or obtain when you use our Website as described in this Privacy Policy or as otherwise disclosed at the time of collection, to:

  * Conduct internal research;
  * Operate and administer our Website;
  * Ensure compliance with our [Terms of Use](https://www.iab.com/terms-of-use/);
  * Respond to your requests for products, services, and/or information;
  * Communicate with you about IAB products, services, events, promotions, and other items we believe will be of interest to you;
  * Fulfill your purchases or registrations; and
  * Provide member services including publishing a directory for members.

**OPERATIONAL SERVICE PROVIDERS, CO-SPONSORS, AND LINKS TO OTHERS**  
We may use third parties for the purpose of administering, operating, configuring our Website, maintaining and providing internal support for our Website (including data storage), and distributing our online, email, messaged, or web-based newsletters and other information. We will refer to these third parties as our “operational service providers.”

Further, our Website may contain or display information from sponsors, co-sponsors, operational service providers, or others that offer to make information, products, and/or services available, and/or that provide opportunities to participate in promotions or engage in activities or that link or redirect your browser to other websites, web pages, materials, or organizations.

Even if we have a relationship with a third party you may encounter or see on our Website, the links or references to third parties or any of their websites, including any cookies or other technology they may use on such websites, are not under our control and they have their own terms, conditions, policies, and practices that apply to you in connection with their websites, including those concerning collection, use and disclosure of your information (including Personal Information).

Some IAB services, such as seminars, educational events, conferences, newsletters, and discussion groups, may be co-sponsored in conjunction with other companies that are not under the control of the IAB. Likewise, such services might also include non-IAB presenters that are also not under the control of the IAB. Whenever we are involved in the provision of such services, we will disclose the name of co-sponsors and non-IAB presenters. When you register for such services, your name, title, and company may be shared with such co-sponsors and non-IAB presenters in order to better tailor our events. Further, when you participate, or engage with, such services, whether online or in-person, you should be aware that any information you provide, which may include Personal Information, may be disclosed to us, co-sponsors, and non-IAB presenters, and that their respective policies, practices, terms and conditions, and not ours, may apply to their collection and use of your information. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our Website or take advantage links or other references, many of which may direct you or your Internet browser to websites or web pages of another party. You should read their privacy statements and the terms and conditions that apply because we are not responsible for any of the terms or conditions, privacy practices, the content, functions, features, activities, and/or transactions you may engage in when you are not using our Website.

**INFORMATION SHARING**  
We may share Personal Information with our operational service providers to assist us in connection with our Website or other services we provide, or as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy. We also reserve the right to share Personal Information:

  * When compelled by a governmental agency, law, regulation, a court or other legal process;
  * If we believe you are, have or may violate any law, regulation or our [Terms of Use](https://www.iab.com/terms-of-use/);
  * If we believe you are or may be a threat to safety, security, property, interests or rights of us or anyone else;
  * In order to investigate, respond to or resolve problems or inquiries or protect, enforce or defend our rights, assets and/or interests; and
  * In a merger, acquisition, change of control, partial or total sale or transfer of assets including in a bankruptcy proceeding, joint venture, or other business combination.

**OPTING OUT**  
If you register on or with our Website, you acknowledge that you will receive information and updates about our Website, products, or services You may opt out of receiving marketing or similar email communications from us by visiting this [form](https://www.iab.com/mailing-preferences/) or by following the unsubscribe instructions we will include in each email we send you. Please note that you may not opt-out of transactional emails related to your account or purchases.

**SECURITY**  
As you may appreciate, the Internet is a public network and we cannot guarantee that communications between you and the IAB or others to, through, or from our Website, will be free from unauthorized access or interference by third parties. By using our Website, you are agreeing to assume this risk and any and all responsibility and liability that may arise. We have put in place reasonable procedures to help safeguard information and we limit access to your Personal Information to only those employees, contractors, service providers, volunteers, or other personnel under appropriate commitments of confidentiality and who need access in order to perform their duties.

**UPDATING PERSONAL INFORMATION ABOUT YOU**  
We will provide you with a mechanism to allow and enable you to correct or update the Personal Information in our current records that we have obtained from you. You can also review and change your Personal Information by contacting us by email at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#2a5a58435c4b49536a434b4804494547) or by telephone at 212.380.4728. Certain Personal Information may not be changed without authentication and you may be asked to provide additional information to allow us to verify your identity in order to change those. If you ask us to remove your Personal Information, we reserve the right to retain as much of your Personal Information and for so long as necessary to comply with our legal, regulatory, internal audit, and record-keeping requirements.

**CONTACT US**  
For questions relating to privacy, we can be contacted at: [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#5d2d2f342b3c3e241d343c3f733e3230) or 212.380.4728 or by mail, proper postage prepaid, at Interactive Advertising Bureau, Inc., 116 E. 27th Street, New York, New York, 10016, Attention: Privacy Administrator.

Be the first to know. Sign up to receive news about the IAB programs, standards, events, classes, and more!
